Let's take a look at how Microsoft
Dynamics 365 Business Central leverages
the power of collaborative applications
to change the way that work gets done.
Meet Adisa, the customer service manager
at Contoso Furniture.
Adisa leads a nimble customer service
team enabled through Business Central.
This morning, Adisa received an email
with a question about a customer's
order.
Using the Business Central Contact
Insights function, she can seamlessly
move from the email to the customer's
record to review their order.
Or she can even add the sender to her
contacts.
As she looks over the order, she
realizes she needs additional
information. So, she adds it to her
agenda for her upcoming sync with her
team, knowing that Gabe, Contoso's
customer service representative for the
account, will be attending the Microsoft
Teams call.
Once the meeting starts, Adisa can
simply paste the link to the customer
card and product in question into the
Teams chat.
From the link Adisa shared, Gabe can
quickly go directly to the information
he needs and is available to drill down
into the product details, bringing the
team up to speed on inventory counts,
delivery dates, order updates, and more.
Gabe updates the product data and order
status based on discussion with the team
on the call, keeping everyone aligned
and the work in motion.
Philip, Contoso's inventory manager, is
also in Teams.
As Adisa shares the Business Central
records, Philip is able to view them
even though he doesn't have a Business
Central license.
Before Contoso implemented Business
Central, Philip may have received the
classic access denied message. But with
Business Central, Philip is granted
read-only access through his Microsoft
365 account, making interdepartmental
collaboration easier and faster than
ever.
This is how Adisa leverages the
collaborative power of Business Central
to give her team and stakeholders in
other departments the information they
need to make decisions, tighten lead
times, and move more product, all while
staying in the flow of work in Microsoft
Teams.
Whether you're in the office or on the
go, Microsoft Dynamics 365 Business
Central has you covered, delivering the
information you need at any time, on any
device.
Business Central allows Contoso to drive
productivity across the business using
the connected functionality and
interoperability with Microsoft 365,
including Microsoft Teams.
Later that afternoon, Gabe is helping a
customer who would like to increase the
order quantity on an open order that is
scheduled to be picked, packed, and
shipped that evening.
Time is of the essence.
Gabe opens the item card in Business
Central to check the on-hand inventory
and confirms there is enough stock to
fulfill the request.
Without leaving the flow of work, Gabe
opens the sales order and increases the
quantity.
But when he tries to save the order, he
gets a notification informing him that
increasing the quantity will push the
total cost beyond the customer's credit
limit.
Gabe knows the order is time-sensitive,
so he quickly opens a Teams chat with
the customer.
In that exchange, the customer tells him
that they made an EFT payment to cover
last week's delivery.
Gabe wonders if maybe Contoso received
the funds but hasn't updated the account
receivable record yet.
To find out, Gabe needs to work with
Tamara in accounts receivable.
Since his team used Microsoft Power
Automate to create a special new
escalation space, the series of steps
Gabe uses in this type of situation is
automated.
Now, with a single click in Business
Central, Gabe can run the automation and
really save time when time is of the
essence.
Here, when Gabe clicks new escalation
space, a new collaborative space in
Microsoft Teams is opened to facilitate
a group chat flow where stakeholders
from across Contoso and his team can
collaboratively work together to solve
the issue.
Once the escalation space is open in
Teams, Gabe adds Tamara to the chat.
Gabe is also able to search for the
company contact in Teams and add them to
the chat as well, bringing everyone
together so they can stay in sync.
After a brief introduction, Gabe
explains that he is trying to increase
the quantity of an existing order, but
that the increase will need special
approval from Tamara because it exceeds
the customer's current credit limit.
With the interoperability of Business
Central, Gabe is able to add a tab that
shows all of the customer invoices and
payments,
adding contextual business data to the
chat.
After understanding the issue, Tamara
switches to Business Central to check
for the electronic funds transfer
payment.
She doesn't see that anything has
arrived yet and lets Gabe know in the
escalation chat.
Tamara is curious about the customer's
payment history. Do they pay on time?
By how much will the credit limit be
exceeded?
She quickly exports a list of customer
payments to Microsoft Excel so she can
easily analyze the account history, and
there it is. It turns out the additional
quantity order is only a marginal
increase in the customer's credit limit,
and the customer has a long history of
on-time payments.
Tamara overrides the warning and
approves the increase, letting Gabe know
in the chat that he can move forward.
In a matter of minutes, the issue is
solved. The additional sales go through
and the customer is delighted.
This is what collaborative applications
are all about, making business data
available broadly to quickly overcome
everyday business challenges.
Let's jump back into our story at
Contoso Furniture and fast forward to
the busiest week before the holidays
when Gabe's email inbox is bursting with
new business.
It seems one of his customers would like
a quote on some new items.
Using Business Central in Outlook, Gabe
brings up the customer's record for easy
reference, giving him valuable insights
about the customer's purchase and
billing history, their payment and
account balance.
Gabe notices the returning customer has
not yet been awarded any discounts
despite always paying for large orders
on time.
In a matter of seconds, Gabe can open
the list of item discounts in Excel and
copy over all special prices and
discounts from another premium customer.
With a click, his edits in Excel are
saved back to Business Central and are
ready to apply.
From Outlook, Gabe can also link
important email attachments to the
customer record in Business Central,
making it easier for his coworkers
across the quote-to-cash cycle to read
up on this customer's unique wishes and
requirements.
He can quickly compose a reply with a
quote based on the products that Outlook
has automatically detected in the
customer's email, all without leaving
his flow of work.
As Gabe checks the PDF of the quote he
just created, he notices the offer on
deliveries isn't up to date.
To fix this, he clicks export layout to
Microsoft Word and makes the changes.
In Word, Gabe modifies the template that
Business Central uses to create the PDFs
of the quote.
He does this and saves the template back
to Business Central.
To raise awareness with his coworkers,
Gabe uses the share link functionality
to circulate the updated template for
review.
The entire sales team now benefits from
the updated sales quote template, saving
everyone time and ensuring Contoso's
customers are presented with consistent
and professional documents.
With the help of collaborative apps
available in Business Central,
information flows at the speed of
business.
Get the tools your team needs to adapt
faster, work smarter, and perform
better.
Tap into the power of the collaborative
applications in Microsoft Dynamics 365
Business Central.